#### CURICULUM VITAE

### Hugo Vieilledent

hugo.vieilledent@gmail.com 46 Mainzer Strasse 12053 [http://hugovieilledent.com] +4915731460179

Berlin

[https://github.com/hugovieilledent]

Thinking and developing honest tools, services and products is what I enjoy. As a front-end developer I put emphasis upon user experiences and cross platform usages, whereas a product developer I focus on building self-explaining easy to use yet powerful tools. My goal is to always discover more to understand and explain.

server

javascript frameworks ember[data, cli], jquery, react (notions)

express.js, micro.js

css

object orientated css3 (oocss), sass, less

suit css naming convention html5, handlebars, jade, haml

markup languages tools

git, npm, bower, grunt, gulp, yeoman, emacs

cms softwares drupal, wordpress, tumblr sketch, photoshop, indesign

### Experience

### =======

## Frontend UX web Developer

Sep 2015 - May 2016, [https://brig.ht] (Berlin, Gernamy)

Developed and designed the consumer-facing frontend of Bright's platform, interface and UX. Architected an Ember pre-2.x application from scratch and kept the product up to date with the latest Ember stable releases (up to 2.5.x).

- Understanding of how a modern web application works end-to-end.
- Develop and document a clean and reusable SCSS styleguide and HTML5 markup
- Worked closely with backend engineers on the API design for new features; also on preventing web client security common attacks by implementing best practices

### Frontend web Developer

Feb 2013 - Aug 2015, [https://kopfwelt.com] (Berlin, Germany)

Developed and maintained many client websites, for small and bigger clients, focusing on clean and effective UX. We took pride in finding creative and simple solutions, for instance to offer CMS-side complete customization of page layouts on [http://lodownmagazine.com].

- Project planification and budgetisation, team management
- Responsive design, pixel perfect, mobile first, fluid layouts
- Contextual and progressive enhancement, responsive images
- Internalisation (l18n) and Localisation (l10n)
- Full cross-browser/cross-device/cross-platform design implementation and testing
- External communication with the design, product, and other groups with the external clients

### Product Developer

~~~~~~~~~~~~

Aug 2014 - current, [http://internet4000.com] (Berlin, remote)

Team of two collaborating on the development of tools and services. Active projects include a music discovery website [https://radio4000.com], an online vinyl store search engine [http://lpepfinder.com].

### Intellectual Property Lawyer Intern

Jan 2012 - Mar 2012, [http://hastatis.com] (Montpellier, France)

Defined and document aspects of a legal protection strategy for the company's incoming main product, a CRM software. Wrote a report on the compagny's Intellectual Property present and future assets (patents, trademarks, domain names, identity...).

- Prepare Trademarks declarations and domain names registration
- Review employment contracts, focus on IP rights and confidentiality terms; organize the recruitment process
- Research and document Copyrights on written and used source codes
- Organize and run training sessions to teams members in order to communicate IP and legal concepts
- Started a company knowledge base to support the teams and recruits

#### Legal Assistant

~~~~~~~~~~

Jun 2008 — Jul 2008, Millau Town Council's Legal and Town Planing departements (Millau, France)

Support to the Legal Team conducting legal researches and document drafting; administrative tasks, legal correspondences in internal and external legal inquiries

### Education

\_\_\_\_\_

Master's degree, Intellectual Property Law

### 2011 – 2012, Université Montpellier I (France)

Provides in depth knowledge and practical skills relating to industrial, literary and artistic property rights for France, Europe and International regions. Deep interest in Web related matters.

- trademark and patent
- copyright and artistic protection
- design protection
- international architecture of Intellectual Property
- counterfeiting and IP legal actions
- IP contracts

Master's thesis: Copyright and Open Science, study of scientific edition (Le droit d'auteur face à l'Open Science - Le Libre au soutien du droit d'auteur dans le marché de l'édition scientifique).

## Master's degree, Political Science and International Relations

2010 - 2011, Københavns Universitet (Denmark)

Courses including Political Analysis, International Relations, International Ethics, Scandinavian Political Systems, Xenophobia and Extreme Right, Cinema and Extreme Right. As a side-project I created a web platform to help foreign students getting in touch with each other, share tips and housing offers, sell their furnitures. It was a ±3000 people community after one semester.

# Bachelor's degree, Political Science and Public Administration

2009 - 2010, Université Montpellier I (France)

Year project: quantitative researches and qualitative methods to build a sociography of the french regions' parliamentary representatives. I also developed and taught a workflow —for flawless group work (10 people)— using collaborating tools such as Dropbox and Google apps.

# Other

- English (bilingual proficiency), german (elementary proficiency),
  french (mother tongue), spanish (professional proficiency)
- Driving licences (car, motorcycle)
- Music producer and dj, [http://200okrecords.com]